Guide to the New-York Historical Society Pictorial Archive 1804-2009 (bulk 1900s-1970s) NYHS-RG 5
New-York Historical Society
- Series IV: Public Programs, 1864, 1941-1990s; 1.62 Linear feet
  - Constitution Lecture Series; New York Film Series, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - A House Divided: Civil War Film Screening and Discussion; Why History Matters Speakers, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Musical Performances, circa 1990-1992 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    Includes performance and/or publicity photographs from various musical groups, including Cherish the Ladies, The Virtuosi Quintet, the Garifuna Ensemble, Duo Lumon-Marquez, Maria Theresa Rodriguez, Los Pleneros de la 21, Sister Sadie and the Famous Biblettes, New York-Buenos Aires Connection, Brave Old World, Shashmaqam, and Music from China.
  - Hillary Clinton at N-YHS, 1990s? (Box 71, Folder 7)
  - Unidentified Public Events, 1960s?-1990s; 0.01 Linear feet (Box 21, Folder 15)
- Series V: Events & Publicity, 1854, 1939-2000s?; 1.2 Linear feet
  The Strawberry Festival and St. Nicholas Festival photographs, ranging from the 1950s into the 1980s appear first. These are followed by other events in chronological order. A few miscellaneous oversize items are found at the end of the container list.
  This series includes photographs of events held by N-YHS that involved public audiences, though sometimes only to a limited or invited extent, or were of a publicity nature. These events included N-YHS's Strawberry Festival, an annual springtime affair for members, and the St. Nicholas Festival, a longtime tradition of jointly celebrating the December holiday from a Netherlands and New Netherlands perspective and N-YHS's anniversary. Other events include presentations of donated objects, N-YHS's sesquicentennial anniversary dinner and reception; commercial photo shoots using N-YHS galleries and objects as backdrop; medal awards; and the History Maker's Gala fundraisers of the 1980s, among others. The series also holds a small number of posters, signage, and other such graphic materials related to N-YHS sponsored events.
  - Print of and identification key to Distinguished Americans at a Meeting of N-YHS in the Chapel of the New York University Building at Washington Square, 1854 (Drawer 12A-B10, Folder 2)
    See also: two copies of "Meeting of the New-York Historical Society in the Chapel of New York University," a print by To. Doney after a painting by J. Gollman, 1854, located in the Print Room's Portrait File, PR 52, Series II, Groups, Oversize, Clubs and Organizations, NYHS Meetings.
  - Semicenntenial (50th) Anniversary Dinner, 1854 (Drawer 12A-B10, Folder 6)
    Includes the original seating chart for the dinner at the Astor House.
  - Strawberry Festival, 1939, 1941 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Strawberry Festival, 1942 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Strawberry Festival, 1946?, 1949 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    Includes 17 photographs and one negative from 1946(?), one photograph from 1949.
  - Strawberry Festival, 1950 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Strawberry Festival, 1951 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Strawberry Festival, 1952 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Strawberry Festival, 1953 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Strawberry Festival, 1954 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Strawberry Festival, 1955 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Strawberry Festival, 1956 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Strawberry Festival (1 of 2), 1957 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Strawberry Festival (2 of 2). Oversize, 1957 (Box 71, Folder 5)
  - Strawberry Festival, 1958 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Strawberry Festival, 1959 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Strawberry Festival, 1950s? (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Strawberry Festival, 1960 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Strawberry Festival, 1961 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Strawberry Festival, 1971, 1973, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    Includes negatives for the 1971 event.
  - Strawberry Festival, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - St. Nicholas Day Party, 1952 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - St. Nicholas Day Party, 1953 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - St. Nicholas Day Party, 1954 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - St. Nicholas Day Party, 1955 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - St. Nicholas Day Party, 1957 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - St. Nicholas Day Party, 1958 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - St. Nicholas Day Party, 1959 (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - St. Nicholas Day Party, 1960-1962 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - St. Nicholas Day Party, 1950s-1960s? (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - St. Nicholas Day Party, 1980-1988 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Battle of Harlem Heights Centennial, 1876 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    Includes photographs of a woodcut depicting the celebration.
  - Gold Medal for Achievement in History, 1931, 1942 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    Includes photographs of presentations to Wilberforce Eames (1931) and to George C.D. Odell (1942).
  - Cruise on the 330th Anniversary of the Discovery of the River by Henry Hudson, 1939 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    Includes photographs of the Hudson Day Line cruise for members sponsored by President George Zabriskie.
  - Laurance Hart (as George Washington?), 1940 February 22 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Unidentified Events & Signage, circa 1944 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    Includes publicity photograph for the Song Spinners and a U.S. Army Signal Corps photograph of a conference of generals. Includes a N-YHS billboard also advertising war bonds.
  - 80th Birthday Card to the New York Fire Department, 1945 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Presentation of the Bell from the "Elizabeth", 1947 October 14 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Loan by N-YHS of Federal Hall Railing for Washington Inauguration Re-enactment, 1949 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Treasure Chest Contest Photo Shoot, 1948 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    Includes pirate-themed publicity shots taken at N-YHS's Port of New York Gallery for Colgate-Palmolive Company's Treasure Chest Contest. Shots feature Corky Crowley and Dennis Day.
  - Cruise Aboard Liberte, 1952 May 6 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Presentation of Tapestry Commemorating Belgian Settlers of New York, 1953 September 22 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Presentation of Model of Tanker SS Socony, 1954 April 14 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Telecast of NBC-TV "Home" Show, 1954 May 13 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Sesquicentennial Celebrations (1 of 2). (Dinner at Union Club; Reception at N-YHS), 1954 May, November (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Sesquicentennial Celebrations (2 of 2). Oversize, 1954 (Drawer 12A-B10, Folder 6)
    Includes an oversize seating chart and two oversize photographs of the dinner at the Union Club. 8x10 versions of these are in the above folder.
  - Chips and Twigs Clothing Photo Shoot, circa 1955 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - National Dairy Council Egg Nog Season Press Event, 1956 December (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Gold Medal Presentation for Distinguished Service to Thomas Streeter, 1957 November 27 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - John Paul Jones Movie Publicity; Photo for Mademoiselle Guest Editor Feature, 1958 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    Includes photographs of actors Robert Stack and Erin O'Brien with a John Paul Jones bust at N-YHS.
  - Lincolniana Exhibition Publicity, 1959 (Box 23, Folder 22)
    Includes photographs of actor Richard Boone, then playing Lincoln on Broadway, in publicity shots for the exhibition opening.
  - Presentation of the Bell from the "Mary Powell", circa 1959 (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Unidentified Reception, 1950s (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - Community Opera Concert at N-YHS, 1968 or 1969 (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - West 76th Street Block Party, 1970 June (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - American Museum of Natural History Outdoor Community Project, 1970 September (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - New York Convention and Visitors Bureau Publicity, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 27)
    Includes photograph of New York's Summer Festival Ambassador and Bureau representative Christine Busini with the Beekman carriage.
  - N-YHS 180th Birthday Gala, 1984 November (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - James Flexner Reception?, 1986 September (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - Palm Beach Party, 1987 February (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - History Makers Gala (Honoring Paul Volcker), 1988 October 31 (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - History Makers Gala (Honoring Malcolm Forbes) (3 folders), 1989 October 30 (Box 24, Folder 1-3)
  - Wine Tasting, 1989 November 16 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - N-YHS Signage at Subway Station and at American Museum of Natural History, 1980s?, 1993 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Reunion Luncheon of Mayor John V. Lindsay and Staffers, Miscellaneous Events, 1995, undated (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Unidentified Events (1 of 2), 1950s-1970s? (Box 24, Folder 7)
    Includes a photograph possibly of Allan Nevins receiving his medal for achievement in history in 1954.
  - Unidentified Events (2 of 2), 1980s-2000s (Box 24, Folder 8)
    Includes photographs of Kenneth Scott with James Thomas Flexner (1989), Tom Wolfe, and others.
  - Unidentified Library Event, 1991 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Rental Publicity Photographs, circa 2000 (Box 24, Folder 10A)
    Includes color photographs and slides publicizing various N-YHS spaces as rental events.
  - Luce Center Opening Reception, 2000 (Box 24, Folder 10B)
  - Oversize Materials, 1940s, 1973 (Drawer 12A-B10, Folder 7)
    Includes a flier for the Strawberry Festival (1944), advertising poster for Mary Black's book Old New York in Early Photographs (1973); subway publicity signage (1940s?); and two posters from the "Remember and Rebuild" event held on July 20, 2002, at the Jacob Javits Center (2002).
- Series VI: Staff Events, 1951-circa 1997; 0.37 Linear feet
  The series is arranged by type of event and chronologically within the type.
  This series includes photographs of events held by and for N-YHS staff members. These primarily include the staff Christmas parties of the 195s and some retirement parties.
  - Christmas Party, 1951 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Christmas Party, 1952 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Christmas Party, 1953 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Christmas Party, 1954 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Christmas Party, 1955 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Christmas Party, 1956 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Christmas Party, 1957 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Christmas Party, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Christmas Party, 1959 (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Christmas Party, Maintenance Staff, 1960 (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Christmas Party, 1950s (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Retirements: R.W.G. Vail; Garrett Winter, 1960 (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Retirements: Garrett Winter. Oversize, 1960 (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - Retirements: Edith Slattery & James Nebbergall; Sally Ryan; Michael Sayles, 1961-1965 (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - Retirements: Joe Rapport; Bill Bailey & Eddie Santrucek, 1971, 1973 (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - Softball Game: N-YHS vs. Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1988 May (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - Fire Alarm & Drill, 1989 (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - Unidentified Staff Events and Gatherings, 1940s-circa 1997 (Box 24, Folder 27)
- Series VII: Trustees, Officers, and Staff, 1918-2003; 0.6 Linear feet
  Images of trustee are followed by officers, then by various staff, though there is some overlap in group shots. A small number of pre-1939 images begins the series and unidentified individuals close the series.
  This series includes portrait, posed and casual photographs of N-YHS trustees, officers and staff members.
  - Early Officers and Board, 1918, 1934, 1939 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    Includes photographs of portrait paintings of Robert Kelby (1918) and Alexander J. Wall (1934). Includes photograph of 1939 Board of Trustees.
  - Board of Trustees. Group Photographs (2 folders), 1950s, 1980s (Box 25, Folder 2-3)
  - Board of Trustees. Other Photographs (2 folders), 1950s-1990s (Box 25, Folder 4-5)
    Includes portraits of Beekman, Bilodean, Butterfield, Kimball, Middendorf, Olds, Pearlstine, Prentis, Streeter, and Van Alstyne, and some informal snapshots of gatherings.
  - Board of Trustees. Other Photographs. Oversize, 1925, 1959, Undated (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - Directors/Chief Executive Officers (2 folders), 1950s-1990s (Box 25, Folder 6-7)
    Includes R.W.G. Vail, James Heslin, James Bell, and Barbara Debs.
  - Various Staff, 1939-2003 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    Includes photographs of Dorothy Barck, Jean Ashton, Mary Black, Holly Hotchner, and James Mooney, among others. Includes a snapshot of at least some of the Library Staff.
  - Unidentified Individuals, 1940s?-1960s? (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Pen drawings of Print Room staff, 1990-1991 (Box 71, Folder 8)
    Scope and Contents
    3 pen drawings by employee Laird A. Ogden. Christmas holiday/winter-themed from 1990, 1991, and undated (perhaps 1989). Depicts various staff members (unidentified by name) of the Print Room.
- Series VIII: (Not Used)
- Series IX: Object Images, 1899-1995; 1.96 Linear feet
  The Object Images series includes photographs of objects, primarily from N-YHS's museum collection, though items from the prints and manuscript collections are also included. The bulk of the photographs include only one particular object, but some photographs include multiple objects or N-YHS staff and others displaying, demonstrating or otherwise interacting with an object. Many of the objects are unidentified and the photographs undated.
  Many of the photographs are of objects not from N-YHS's collections, and these were likely used in exhibition or other research, such as found in the set of folders with New York City views. Also along these lines are a number of photographs taken in 1949 of the Prentis Murphy home in Connecticut that show the New England furnishings that would be installed at N-YHS in 1951.
  The series is arranged in alphabetical order by subject matter of the photographs. Most of these subjects were presumably taken from original folders. Additional photographs integrated in 2015 were given subject titles by the processing archivist. A small number of miscellaneous oversize items are found at the end of the container list.
  - Advertising, Undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Alland, Alexander, 1949 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    Includes photographic prints and contact sheets made by Alexander Alland of photographs from the Bracklow collection (and perhaps others).
  - American Revolution, Undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - American School Paintings, Undated (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Ames, Ezra, Undated (Box 26, Folder 5)
    Includes a photograph, among others, of a gallery of works by Ames.
  - Audubon, 1960s-1980s (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Audubon Writing Desk, Change Purse, Death Mask, 1950s, Undated (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Bowling Green (Object 1910.8), Undated (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Bowls, Pots, Spoons, Cups, Undated (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Catlin Drawings, 1969 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Chairs, Couches, Tables, Stove, Undated (Box 26, Folder 11)
    Includes a photograph, likely taken in N-YHS's Second Avenue building, of the "Marie Antoinette" chair before reupholstering.
  - Cherry Valley, NY, circa 1880-1890 (Mrs. Arther Taft Collection), Undated (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Chests & Trunks, Undated (Box 26, Folder 13)
    Includes photographs of a hair trunk.
  - Coaches, 1986, Undated (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Cole, Thomas, Undated (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Copley, John Singleton (Self-Portrait), Undated (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Crawford, Thomas (The Indian sculpture, Object 1875.4), Undated (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Currency, Undated (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Dolls, 1995, Undated (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Draper, Ruth, Undated (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Drawings, Undated (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - Durand, Asher B., Undated (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - Duyckinck, Gerardus, Undated (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - Eagles (Sculptures, Textiles, Pottery, Plates), Undated (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - Earl, Ralph, undated (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - European Collection, Undated (Box 26, Folder 26)
  - Fire Department, Undated (Box 26, Folder 27)
  - Flags, American, Undated (Box 26, Folder 28)
  - Flag (Banner), Pewterer's (Object 1903.12), 1974 (Box 26, Folder 29)
    Includes photographs of banner carried by Society of Pewterer's of New York City in procession of July 23, 1788, celebrating New York's ratification of the Constitution. Photographs are before and after 1974 restoration by conservator Katherine Scott.
  - Fourth of July (July 4), Undated (Box 26, Folder 30)
  - Gavels, Undated (Box 26, Folder 31)
  - Glass, 1992? (Box 26, Folder 32)
  - Globes, Undated (Box 26, Folder 33)
  - Groups of People (1 of 2), 1899-circa 1930s (Box 26, Folder 34)
  - Groups of People (2 of 2). Oversize, 1899-circa 1930s (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - Hill, John W., Undated (Box 26, Folder 35)
  - Hill, Thomas (Yosemite Valley), Undated (Box 26, Folder 36)
  - Hooglandt, Anna. Account Book, Undated (Box 26, Folder 37)
    Includes negatives of various pages of the manuscript (1729-1753).
  - Hudson River School, Undated (Box 26, Folder 38)
  - In Brief, Undated (Box 26, Folder 39)
    Includes a color transparency of George W. Flagg's Lady Jane Grey Preparing for Execution and a slide of a print concerning the purchase of Manhattan Island.
  - Jarvis, John Wesley, Undated (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Johnson, Eastman (Old Kentucky Home), Undated (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Lafayette, Undated (Box 27, Folder 3A)
  - Leadbeater Drugstore, 1987? (Box 27, Folder 3B)
  - Lighting Devices, [1954], Undated (Box 27, Folder 4)
    Includes photographs from exhibitions Early American Arts and Crafts and Early American Lighting Devices.
  - Lincoln, Abraham, Undated (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Manuscript Material, Undated (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Maps, Undated (Box 27, Folder 7)
    Includes a color transparency of A Description of the Towne of Mannados or New Amsterdam and three other color slides.
  - Maritime, Undated (Box 27, Folder 8)
    Includes Robert Fulton and Clermont-related objects, as well as ships, bells, astrolabe.
  - Mary Powell (Ship & Bell), Undated (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Medals, Seals, Jewelry, Rings, Watches, Buckles, Arm Bands, Gorgets, Undated (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Miniature on Ivory of Mrs. Robert Lenox (Object 1950.244), Undated (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Mummified Bull, Undated (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Needlework, 1943, Undated (Box 27, Folder 13)
    Includes objects from the Mrs. J. Insley Blair collection.
  - New York City (1 of 3). Views to Circa 1860, Undated (Box 27, Folder 14)
    This set of folders includes photographs of landscapes, buildings, street scenes, trolleys, elevated railways and their construction, wharves, rivers, Central Park, and other New York scenes. The first folder of early views includes photographs of paintings, prints, and other formats depicting subjects from the colonial period to the mid-nineteenth century.
  - New York City (2 of 3). Views from Circa 1860 to Circa 1930, Undated (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - New York City (3 of 3). Views from Circa 1930 and Later, Undated (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - New-York Historical Society. General, Undated (Box 27, Folder 17)
    Includes photographs of membership certificates, images, correspondence, and other items, mostly 19th century, from the N-YHS archives.
  - New-York Historical Society. Medals, Seals, Tablets (1 of 2), Undated (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - New-York Historical Society. Medals, Seals, Tablets (2 of 2). Oversize, 1915, 1917, Undated (Box 70, Folder 1)
    Includes oversize renderings of N-YHS anniversary medals, a sketch of a memorial tablet for Andrew Warner (1915), and a sketch of a tablet to be placed by N-YHS at the site of Audubon's home (1917).
  - New-York Historical Society. Images from the Quarterly, Undated (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Peale, Charles Wilson, Undated (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Peale, Rembrandt, Undate (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Pennsylvania Dutch (Bird Sculptures), Undated (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Perry, Matthew C., Undated (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Pewter, circa 1920s?, Undated (Box 28, Folder 5)
    Includes early twentieth century photographs of the Nash Collection of pewter presented by Samuel V. Hoffman.
  - Political Campaigns, Undated (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Portraits, Undated (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Pottery, Undated (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Poughkeepsie, NY, Undated (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Prentis Murphy, Katherine, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    Includes photographs of the home of Mrs. Katherine Prentis Murphy in Westbrook, Connecticut, including her collection of 17th and 18th century New England furnishings.
  - Print Matter, Undated (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Printed Textiles, Undated (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Quilts, Undated (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Revolver & Powder Horns, Undated (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Sculpture, Undated (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Shakespeare in New York (Exhibition?), 1981? (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Silver, Undated (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Spinning Wheels & Looms (Colonial), Undated (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - Stieffel, Herman, Undated (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - Stuart, Gilbert, Undated (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Subway, Undated (Box 28, Folder 21)
    See also the New York City object folders above.
  - Tiffany Lamps, Undated (Box 28, Folder 22)
    Includes color contact sheets and negatives.
  - Tools, Chains, Hardware, Undated (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - Trinity Church, Undated (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - Truant Sculpture by Ives (1945.494), 1988 (Box 28, Folder 25)
  - Unidentified, Undated (Box 28, Folder 26)
  - Uniform, Clothing, Undated (Box 28, Folder 27)
    Includes photograph of the full dress uniform of Commodore Thomas Tingey (1750-1829).
  - Vanderlyn, John, Undated (Box 28, Folder 28)
  - Victorius Volunteer (Painting), Undated (Box 28, Folder 29)
  - World War I Posters, Undated (Box 28, Folder 30)
  - Slides for Talks, 1990s? (Box 72, Folder 1)
  - Oversize Images, 1928, Undated (Drawer 12A-B10, Folder 8)
    Includes a mounted photograph of an artwork The Spirit of America [?], presented by the artist (1928); Audubon prints; reproductions of a 1782 map; and labels for Ottin's Triumphal March of the Republic, a George Washington desk, and furniture from Federal Hall.
- Series X. (Not Used)
  This series formerly included architectural plans concerning N-YHS buildings. These plans were moved to different record groups in 2015-16. Architectural plans from prior to the 1960s are now found with other buildings-related matter in New-York Historical Society Original Building Planning & Construction Records (NYHS-RG 3). Plans related to proposed and actual renovations from the 1960s to the 1990s are in the New-York Historical Society building renovations and maintenance records (NYHS-RG 4).
- Series XI. Negatives, circa 1900-1990s; 11.38 Linear feet
  The Negatives series includes the negatives for many of the photographic prints found in the other series of the Pictorial Archive record group. It also likely includes some images for which there are not prints. Images include those of exhibitions, buildings (interior and exterior), programs and events, objects, and staff. Formats are both glass and film of various sizes (8x10, 5x7, 4x5, and 35 mm strips). Further information on the subject matter of negatives and the approximate number of related negatives for each subject is included in the container list below. Each negative is individually enclosed in an envelope that often includes descriptive information that is not always noted on the prints, such as date, event, and names of people in the image.
  Negatives included in this series are only those that were held in the N-YHS Print Room's negative files. Other negatives were found in some of the folders of prints and were left in those folders; see the above series descriptions for those negatives.
  For conservation purposes, the negatives were arranged and housed in boxes by format and by size. Glass slides are boxed separately from film. Within each format, 8x10, 5x7, and 4x5 size envelopes are boxed separately. Generally, the envelope size corresponds with the size of the negative, but some envelopes hold smaller negatives. Most notably, the small 35 mm strips are held in 8x10 sheets/envelopes.